# EDNA GANESHA GONZALEZ RIVERA

Edmonds, WA

Phone: +1(206)710 5111 | Email: edna.ganesha.gr@gmail.com

LinkedIn: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/eggr">https://www.linkedin.com/in/eggr</a>

GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/enanesh">https://github.com/enanesh</a>

Portfolio: <a href="https://enanesh.github.io/edna-portfolio-react/">https://enanesh.github.io/edna-portfolio-react/</a>

# PROFILE SUMMARY

My background has been primarily in finance, where I developed strong analytical and problem-solving skills. However, I have always been drawn to technology and the endless possibilities it provides. With the increasing demand for technology solutions in every industry, I believe that this is the right time for me to make this transition to full-stack development.

### PROFESSIONAL SKILL

#### HARD SKILLS

- JavaScript, HTML, CSS,
- REACT
- Python
- Databases:SQL, MongoDb.
- CSS:Frameworks:Tailwind,bootstrap,bulma.
- MERN,graphQl, node\_modules, GitHub, Express,mongoose,@apolloserver,heroku.

#### SOFT SKILLS

- TeamworK.
- Communication skills.
- Problem-solving.
- Active listening.
- Time management and organization
- Work ownership

### WORK EXPERIENCE

#### **Financial Analyst**

<u>Jáuregui y Del Valle, S.C., Mexico City</u>

Sep 2018 - May 2019 (9 months)

My job tasks included ensuring accurate billing, tracking and reconciling financial transactions, preparing financial reports, and maintaining financial records. I also collaborated with cross-functional teams to analyze accounts receivable and provide insights for strategic decision-making.

#### **Accomplishments**

- Successfully increased invoice collection by 9% through implementing and improving collection procedures, resulting in a significant increase in revenue and cash flow for the company.
- Conducted regular reviews of accounting procedures and identified areas for improvement, resulting in increased efficiency and productivity.

#### **Account Executive (Finance)**

AON Benfield Mexico Reinsurance Intermediary . Mexico City.

Nov 2012 - Nov 2014 (2 yrs 1 mo)

As an accountant in the finance team, I was responsible for monthly billing and reporting directly to the Latin America CFO. I attended internal and external audits, collaborated with the CFO to forecast revenue and expenses, and participated in the restructuring and alignment of fiduciary accounts. I was diligent and detail-oriented, ensuring accuracy and compliance with regulations at all times. Through my work, I gained valuable experience in financial analysis and reporting, as well as in managing and optimizing financial processes for the organization.

- Contributed to the team effort in obtaining financial statement rulings for 2014 and 2015.
- Achieved record time of 2 months to meet regulatory requirements for Revenue Solvency II of reinsurance intermediary companies.
- · Suspendisse fringilla et libero nec commodo. In hac habitasse platea dictumst.
- Designed and implemented an effective archive system for tracking billed revenue and payments.
- Participated in control strategy implementation to achieve revenue forecasted goals, resulting in a 16% increase in annual revenue.

#### Financial Analyst Jr.

Apr 2016 - May 2018 (2 yrs,2 mo)

Michael Page International, Mexico City.

I learned the importance of teamwork and gained hands-on experience in managing payroll, settlements, accounts payable, and accounts receivable. I collaborated closely with the accounting team to ensure accurate financial record-keeping and reporting. Through this experience, I developed a strong attention to detail, problem-solving skills, and the ability to work under tight deadlines.

## EDUCATION COLLEGE

#### Accounting/Bachelor's Degree

Universidad Latinoamericana, Mexico City Average of 87 out of a 100

#### COURSES

- Ada developers Academy: Ada Build Live
- CodeAcademy:Learn Python 3, Code Fondations, Learn Git and GitHub,Learn JavaScript,Explore SD.
- Edx: CS50
- Coding with Mosh: Complete Python Mastery
- Fazt(YouTube):Introduction to Databases, Web Development with Projects, MERN stack, Object Oriented Programming, REACT with Projects, and many others.
- Web Dev Simplified.

#### VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

"Unidos - Cuernavaca, Mexico" is an organization dedicated to promoting social integration for people(mostly Kids) with disabilities. Use to help in integration activities and getting donations for x-mas presents.

"STEM like a girl - Seattle,WA" - is a non-profit organization based in Seattle that aims to inspire and empower girls and young women to pursue careers in science, technology, engineering, and math (STEM) fields. Setting up for events